DANIEL MONTES GIL

Email: LinkedIn: Portfolio:

dmontesgil@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/danielmontesgil/ danielmontesgil.github.io/

Executive Summary

Enthusiastic and dedicated Software Engineer with over four years of experience working and communicating with multi-disciplinary teams. My skills include proficiency in C#, Unity Engine, Playfab, and C++, and experience with multiplayer game frameworks such as Photon and Colyseus. I am highly experienced in working under the Scrum methodology. Team player that has worked on projects such as Zynga's Core Game Engine, used for the most game teams inside Zynga, Table and Taste EA game, and The Project Blue Book game based on a History Channel series.

Technical Skills

- C#, C++
- Unity 3D, Unreal Engine
- AR/VR/XR in Unity
- NuGet
- Agile/Scrum, Atlassian Tools
- Git, PlasticSCM
- PC/Mobile
- Microsoft Azure Playfab
- Jenkins

Relevant Experience

Globant

Software Engineer

July 2022 – Current | Medellín, Colombia

Client: Zynga

- Designed and implemented a solution using reflection to keep a memory profiler package working after an update that made some classes internal.
- Added unit tests in memory profiler to verify data consistency.
- Worked with Zynga stakeholders to architect and implement new functionality to distribute Zynga's core game engine inside Unity, speeding up installation and usage by an average of 50%.
- Developed common NuGet library using NuGet.Protocol to distribute Zynga's core game engine.
- Developed a system utilizing Zynga's track API to conduct comprehensive analytics on the new distribution functionality
- Implement, maintain and review reliable code using C#.
- Increased Code Coverage in 5% using UnitTest in Unity.
- Perform builds, tests, and other basic CI/CD tasks using Jenkins.

Software Engineer

April 2022 – July 2022 | Medellín, Colombia

Client: Globant

- Designes and implemented a multiplayer VR experience in Unity.
- Integrated various libraries, including XR Toolkit, 3D WebView, Playfab for data handling, Photon as the multiplayer, and used WebSocket protocol to listen to events.
- Worked with 3D artist to import and animate assets and sync them over the network.

Software Engineer

July 2021 – March 2022 | Medellín, Colombia

Client: Glu Mobile, Electronic Arts

- Redesigned and implemented the game's rewards flow, including the skip animation, reducing the time between matches and giving the player more control on what to see during rewards.
- Improved the features review process by 20% using videos during development.
- Implemented new loading screens using information from EA's content tool.
- Designed and implemented dynamic HUD widgets to show new and in-progress goals.

Wizard Fun Factory

Junior Software Engineer

May 2020 – December 2020 | Medellín, Colombia

Client: Pikpok

- Developed the save system to allow players to save and load their game progress seamlessly.
- Integrated tournaments and rewards systems, providing players with exciting challenges and incentives for progression.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure a cohesive gaming experience.

Education

- Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana Bachelor's Degree in Digital Entertainment Design Engineering | Graduated in 2018
- Courses and Certifications

Languages

Spanish: NativeGerman: Basic proficiency

English: Professional proficiency

Projects

- Zynga's Core Game Engine (Zynga, 2023) Unity/Andriod/iOS/Steam, Zynga's game engine developed in C# and used for most of the Unity game teams in Zynga. Several libraries that perform common game tasks.
- Project Blue Book Hidden Mysteries (Three Gates AB, 2020) Android/iOS, History Channel official game based on the Project Blue Book TV series.
- Unnamed Project (Own Project, not released, 2018) PC, King of the hill game, started as a GGJ project, Indie Prize Finalist and showed in Los Angeles 2019.
- Master Bounce (Own Project, released in 2020) Android, Arcade game.
- Rivals Stars® Basketball (Pikpok, released in 2021) Android/iOS, basketball card game. Port from C++ to C# using Untiy Engine.